{"test_questions": [[{"question": "During the carboxylation phase of the Calvin cycle, CO2 combines with", "opta": "ribulose 1,5 - bisphosphate", "optb": "phosphoglyceraldehyde", "optc": "pyruvic acid", "optd": "oxaloacetic acid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following groups contain(s) many unique coenzymes, such as coenzyme M and coenzyme F420?", "opta": "Sulfate-reducing bacteria", "optb": "Methanotrophs (methane-oxidizing microbes)", "optc": "Methanogens (methane-producing microbes)", "optd": "Acetogens (acetigens; acetate-producing microbes)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the passive diffusion, solute molecules cross the membrane as a result of", "opta": "concentration difference", "optb": "pressure difference", "optc": "ionic difference", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an oxygenic photosynthesis, the green and the purple bacteria do not use which of the following one as an electron source?", "opta": "H2O", "optb": "H2", "optc": "H2S", "optd": "S (elemental sulphur)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Radioisotopes are frequently used in the study of cells. Assume a culture of E. coli is grown in a culture medium containing radioactive phosphorous. At the end of 48 hours, it is expected to find the radioactive label located in", "opta": "enzymes", "optb": "RNA", "optc": "phospholipids", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Assimilatory sulfate reduction involves the nucleotide __________ during the incorporation of H2S in the production of __________ .", "opta": "ATP; methionine", "optb": "ATP; cytosine", "optc": "UTP; cytosine", "optd": "GTP; cytosine", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The chlorophyll molecules used by eucaryotes and cyanobacteria absorb radiant energy in the____________portion(s) of the visible spectrum.", "opta": "red", "optb": "green", "optc": "red and blue", "optd": "green and ultraviolet", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In aerobic respiration, the terminal electron acceptor is", "opta": "oxygen", "optb": "nitrogen", "optc": "hydrogen", "optd": "nitrate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct?", "opta": "Phosphate repression can not be eliminated by optimization of nutrient medium, deregulated medium must be used as production strains", "optb": "Phosphate repression can be eliminated by optimization of nutrient medium, deregulated medium must be used as production strains", "optc": "Phosphate repression can be eliminated by optimization of nutrient medium, regulated medium must be used as production strains", "optd": "Phosphate repression can not be eliminated by optimization of nutrient medium, regulated medium must be used as production strains", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The acquisition energy by glucose fermentation requires", "opta": "substrate-level phosphorylation", "optb": "electron transport of electrons from NADH", "optc": "long-chain fatty acid oxidation", "optd": "the enzyme formic-hydrogen lyase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "High energy transfer compounds are capable of", "opta": "accepting large amounts of free energy", "optb": "transferring large amounts of free energy", "optc": "measuring free energy", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Dolichol phosphate is", "opta": "a complex lipid involved in docking vesicles with the plasma membrane", "optb": "the anchor on which sugars assemble before transfer to proteins", "optc": "a chaperone used in protein folding", "optd": "a product of phospholipase C activation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The reactions of the cell that are carried out for capturing energy are called", "opta": "catabolism", "optb": "metabolism", "optc": "anabolism", "optd": "activation energy", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In establishing proton gradient for chemiosmotic ATP generation by aerobic respiration the terminal electron acceptor is", "opta": "nitrate", "optb": "oxygen", "optc": "sulfate", "optd": "CO2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If \u0394G of a chemical reaction is positive in value and keq  is less than 1 then the chemical reaction will", "opta": "proceed in reverse direction", "optb": "proceeed in forward direction", "optc": "not take place in any of the direction", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The reaction, where small precursor molecules are assembled into larger organic molecules is referred as", "opta": "anabolism", "optb": "catabolism", "optc": "metabolism", "optd": "any of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following nucleoside diphosphates is used most often in carbohydrate anabolism?", "opta": "Uridine diphosphate", "optb": "Adenosine diphosphate", "optc": "Guanine diphosphate", "optd": "Thymine diphosphate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DAHP synthetase catalyzes the condensation of", "opta": "erythrose-4-phosphate", "optb": "phosphoenol pyruvate", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "phenylalanine", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Phosphate is considered to restrict the induction of", "opta": "primary metabolites", "optb": "secondary metabolites", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Free energy change (\u0394G) of a reaction is referred as the amount of energy", "opta": "liberated during reaction", "optb": "taken up during reaction", "optc": "liberated or taken up during reaction", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following does not produce oxygen as a product of photosynthesis?", "opta": "Oak trees", "optb": "Purple sulfur bacteria", "optc": "Cyanobacteria", "optd": "Phytoplankton", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When acetate is the sole source of carbon for some microorganisms, the cycle which is used, is called", "opta": "pentose phosphate pathway", "optb": "glycolyic pathway", "optc": "glyoxylate pathway", "optd": "oxaloacetate pathway", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hexose monophosphate pathway is also known as", "opta": "phosphogluconate pathway", "optb": "oxaloacetate pathway", "optc": "malate pathway", "optd": "fumerate pathway", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If radioactive bicarbonate was supplied to bacterial cells, which were actively synthesizing fatty acids, it is expected to find the bulk of the radioactivity in", "opta": "cellular bicarbonate", "optb": "the fatty acids", "optc": "the cytoplasmic membrane", "optd": "nucleic acids", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Standard free energy change (\u0394G) can be expressed as", "opta": "\u0394G\u00b0 = -RTlnkeq", "optb": "\u0394G\u00b0 = RTlnkeq", "optc": "\u0394G\u00b0 = R/Tlnkeq", "optd": "\u0394G\u00b0 = -RT/lnkeq", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The glyoxylate cycle is used by some microorganisms when___________ is the sole carbon source.", "opta": "acetate", "optb": "nitrate", "optc": "carbon dioxide", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Incorporation of atmospheric N2to NH4+ occurs via the process of", "opta": "assimilatory nitrate reduction", "optb": "transamination", "optc": "deamination", "optd": "nitrogen fixation", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The role of bacteriophyll in an oxygenic photosynthesis is to", "opta": "reduce ferridoxin directly", "optb": "reduce NADP directly", "optc": "use light energy to energize an electron", "optd": "transfer electrons to an intermediate in the sulfide oxidation pathway", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "TCA cycle functions in", "opta": "catabolic reactions", "optb": "anabolic reactions", "optc": "amphibolic reactions", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Entner-Doudoroff pathway is found in", "opta": "aerobic prokaryotes", "optb": "anaerobic prokaryotes", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "aerobic eukaryotes", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Anoxygenic photosynthetic bacteria oxidize", "opta": "water", "optb": "oxgyen", "optc": "sulfide", "optd": "ammonia", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following(s) is/are the products of the light reactions of photosynthesis?", "opta": "ATP only", "optb": "NADPH only", "optc": "ATP and O2 only", "optd": "ATP, NADPH, and O2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following catalyze liberation of orthophosphate from organic P compounds and inorganic pyrophosphate ?", "opta": "Alkaline phosphates", "optb": "Oxidoreductase", "optc": "Protease", "optd": "Hydrogenase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For each glucose molecule broken down, there are______________number of reduced coenzymes to be oxidized.", "opta": "12", "optb": "8", "optc": "6", "optd": "4", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As the electron flow through the chains, much of their free energy is conserved in the form of ATP. This process is called", "opta": "oxidative phosphorylation", "optb": "electromotive potential", "optc": "dehydrogenations", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Digestive reactions where large molecules are broken down into smaller ones are referred as", "opta": "anabolism", "optb": "catabolism", "optc": "metabolism", "optd": "biosynthesis", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Phosphate regulation has been observed in the production of", "opta": "alkaloids", "optb": "antibiotics", "optc": "gibberelins", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Most of the energy in aerobic respiration of glucose is captured by", "opta": "substrate-level phosphorylation", "optb": "electron transport of electrons from NADH", "optc": "long-chain fatty acid oxidation", "optd": "the enzyme formic-hydrogen lyase", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During the reduction phase of the Calvin cycle, phosphoglyceric acid is reduced to______utilizing________as the reduction source.", "opta": "phosphoglyceraldehyde; NADPH+H+", "optb": "phosphoglyceraldehyde; NADH+H+", "optc": "ribulose 1,5 - bisphosphate; NADH+H+", "optd": "pyruvic acid; NADPH+H+", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In order to get inorganic phosphorous into organic compounds, the phosphate ion is incorporated via", "opta": "substrate level phosphorylation", "optb": "oxidative phosphorylation", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "DNA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The phosphate inhibition in the clavine formation with Claviceps SD58, can be counteracted by the addition of", "opta": "alanine", "optb": "methionine", "optc": "tryptophan", "optd": "lysine", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The major route for incorporation of ammonia (NH4+) into organic compounds is via", "opta": "reduction of pyruvate or alpha-ketoglutarate by enzymes", "optb": "atmospheric nitrogen fixation", "optc": "oxidation of pyruvate", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The specific enzyme/(s) of the glyoxylate cycle is/are", "opta": "isocitrate lyase", "optb": "malate synthase", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "anaplerotic", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If \u0394G of a chemical reaction has a negative value, the reaction", "opta": "releases energy", "optb": "requires energy", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The catabolic reaction, pentose-phosphate exists in", "opta": "prokaryotic cells", "optb": "eukaryotic cells", "optc": "prokaryotic and eukaryotic cells both", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Entner - Doudoroff pathway is not found in", "opta": "aerobic prokaryotes", "optb": "anaerobic prokaryotes", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "eukaryotes", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Aerobic catabolism of glucose yields how much energy (ATP synthesized) relative to glucose fermentation?", "opta": "Slightly less", "optb": "About the same", "optc": "Twice as much", "optd": "More than 10 times as much", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bacteriochlorophylls used by the anoxygenic bacteria have absorbance maxima located in the_____portion(s) of the spectrum.", "opta": "green", "optb": "blue", "optc": "ultraviolet", "optd": "infrared", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The relationship between an oxidation-reduction potential difference and the standard free energy change is (where n is the number of moles of electron transferred, F= Faraday's constant and E\u00b0= standard oxidation-reduction potential difference)", "opta": "\u0394G\u00b0 = -nFE\u00b0", "optb": "\u0394G\u00b0 = nFE\u00b0", "optc": "\u0394G\u00b0 = -nFlnE\u00b0", "optd": "\u0394G\u00b0 = nFlnE\u00b0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "ATPase", "opta": "synthesizes ATP, coupled to transfer of extracellular protons into the cell", "optb": "extrudes protons from the cell coupled to the hydrolysis of ATP to ADP", "optc": "is the enzyme that incorporates ATP into messenger RNA", "optd": "carries out each of the reactions indicated in (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is responsible for phosphate solubilization?", "opta": "Streptococcus", "optb": "Streptomyces", "optc": "Bacillus", "optd": "Clostridium", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Phosphate deregulated mutants are", "opta": "less sensitive to phosphate regulation", "optb": "moderately sensitive to phosphate regulation", "optc": "highly sensitive to phosphate regulation", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The mechanism of passive or facilitated diffusion require", "opta": "metabolic energy", "optb": "concentration of solute against an electrochemical gradient", "optc": "accumulation of solute against an electrochemical gradient", "optd": "accumulation or concentration of solute against an electrochemical gradient", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Nitrogen fixation is a process that requires", "opta": "energy", "optb": "an anaerobic environment", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "an aerobic environment", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bacteriochlorophyll differs from chlorophyll in what way?", "opta": "The chelated metal in bacteriochlorophyll is not Mg", "optb": "There are chemical differences between the two chlorophyll in their side (R) groups", "optc": "They have different absorption spectra", "optd": "Both (b) and (c)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Radioisotopes are frequently used in the study of cells. Assume a culture of E. coli is grown in a culture medium containing radioactive sulphur. At the end of 48 hours, it is expected to find the radioactive label located in", "opta": "DNA", "optb": "enzymes", "optc": "RNA", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}